<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-05-23T02:57:58-05:00</updated><id>/</id><title>Martini Software</title><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><entry><title>The future of chef-rvm</title><link href="/2014/09/02/the-future-of-chef-rvm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The future of chef-rvm" /><published>2014-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2014/09/02/the-future-of-chef-rvm</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2014/09/02/the-future-of-chef-rvm.html">&lt;p&gt;It was over a year ago that I asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fnichol&quot;&gt;Fletcher&lt;/a&gt; if I could help him with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fnichol/chef-rvm&quot;&gt;chef-rvm&lt;/a&gt; and he enthusiastically said yes. If you have been following or recently glancing at the project, you&amp;#39;ll notice it has been a little while since the last release. To put it short, both Fletcher and I have been extremely busy with other projects, work, and life in general. I personally had some &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/05/02/burnout-my-struggle-with-imposter-syndrome.html&quot;&gt;demons to battle&lt;/a&gt; and disconnected from all of my projects at once to let me recuperate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal time off as mentioned before has helped me put things into perspective and let me rejoin projects at my own pace. If you&amp;#39;ve ever thought about taking on open source in a maintainer role be sure to build in some break time. Open Source is literally &lt;em&gt;a second job&lt;/em&gt; that answers to everyone&amp;#39;s needs, but generally pays nothing while asking for everything and can sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://sethvargo.com/leaving-chef/&quot;&gt;invoke hatred&lt;/a&gt; from your users. It is emotionally taxing in a similar way to being at a Customer Service desk where you are bombarded with pleas for help charged with a modicum of frustration. This isn&amp;#39;t a personal cry for help, but your glimpse into my perspective of things. I enjoy helping others and lending a hand where I can. This is why I wanted a break and not a new career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The road to 1.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fletcher and I have been in a few discussions about where to take chef-rvm because of the rapidly changing &lt;a href=&quot;https://supermarket.chef.io/&quot;&gt;Chef community&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.vialstudios.com/the-environment-cookbook-pattern/&quot;&gt;cookbook patterns&lt;/a&gt;. In the sections below I will highlight the major changes and a little reasoning behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Moving to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.chef.io/custom_resources.html&quot;&gt;LWRP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the initial decisions was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fnichol/chef-rvm/pull/235&quot;&gt;a weekend experiment to re-write&lt;/a&gt; the cookbook as an LWRP that is currently in a branch. So far this pattern is working out better than expected and will help us shed the need for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wayneeseguin/rvm-gem&quot;&gt;rvm-gem&lt;/a&gt; that is no longer maintained by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rvm.io/&quot;&gt;rvm&lt;/a&gt; team. We are pioneering a better way to execute with the rvm environment via Chef. The RVM maintainer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mpapis&quot;&gt;Michael Papis&lt;/a&gt; is helping us on this front to make sure we&amp;#39;re doing things correctly by rvm for execution. This change will also help us prepare for the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rvm/rvm&quot;&gt;RVM 2.0&lt;/a&gt; release by leveraging more of rvm command api.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Declaring bankruptcy on issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have looked at the repository lately, issues have been piling up over time. Some of them dating back &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fnichol/chef-rvm/issues/68&quot;&gt;over 2 years ago&lt;/a&gt; and still labeled as &amp;#39;in progress&amp;#39;. Fletcher and I are both extremely sorry for the lack of response or follow-up from us on many of these issues. Again as mentioned before, we have been neglecting the project for some time now. In order to move forward with 1.0, we will be closing any issues older than 6 months. Each one will contain a message encouraging the issue creator to follow up with updated information and re-open the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Adding a Code of Conduct &amp;amp; Contribution Guide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help foster equality and respect, we will be adopting a code of conduct along with a contribution guide. The Chef community has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chef.io/blog/2014/08/27/behaving-responsibly-in-the-chef-community/&quot;&gt;begun to adopt a policy&lt;/a&gt; and we will be adding something similar to the repository as a reminder. Remember there are humans at the other end of that github issue, email, or comment and I personally want this cookbook to be as friendly and inviting as the Ruby community itself. To put it bluntly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/sethvargo/dealing-with-the-demands-of-the-open-source-community&quot;&gt;don&amp;#39;t be an asshole&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Adding more maintainers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The elephant in the room I wanted to address here is adding more maintainers to the chef-rvm project. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fnichol/chef-rvm/issues/232&quot;&gt;an open issue&lt;/a&gt; for this and it will get addressed past the 1.0 release by Fletcher since it is his project. Fletcher and I will be at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://summit.chef.io/&quot;&gt;Chef Community Summit&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle. If you are attending, we encourage you to say hello to either one of us. We would love to arrange a little hack session while there if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2.0 and beyond&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the future hold beyond 1.0? Once 1.0 is stable and out there, chef-rvm will version along side the rvm project via &lt;a href=&quot;http://semver.org/&quot;&gt;semver&lt;/a&gt;. The 1.x releases will be rvm 1.x compatible while the chef-rvm 2.x releases will target rvm2. There has been discussion between Fletcher and I about shedding the data bag based recipes into a separate wrapper cookbook to maintain the current 0.9 functionality and keep the LWRP cookbook small and focused. We&amp;#39;re a little bit off from that decision and will probably open it as a github issue to discuss it with the community at large and go from there. As mentioned above, we&amp;#39;ll be looking to add more people with commit access in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>It was over a year ago that I asked Fletcher if I could help him with chef-rvm and he enthusiastically said yes. If you have been following or recently glancing at the project, you&amp;#39;ll notice it has been a little while since the last release. To put it short, both Fletcher and I have been extremely busy with other projects, work, and life in general. I personally had some demons to battle and disconnected from all of my projects at once to let me recuperate.</summary></entry><entry><title>Burnout: My struggle with Imposter Syndrome</title><link href="/2014/05/02/burnout-my-struggle-with-imposter-syndrome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burnout: My struggle with Imposter Syndrome" /><published>2014-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2014/05/02/burnout--my-struggle-with-imposter-syndrome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2014/05/02/burnout-my-struggle-with-imposter-syndrome.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the assumption from others is that my job is easy. I sit in front of a computer all day and type on a keyboard. How stressful is that? Very. I always equate it to running a marathon in your head. You are constantly practicing, making quick decisions, acting on instinct, always driving, and generally being amplified by Caffeine. When you begin piling on all those responsibilities and doing too much for too long, your brain will give up and you&amp;#39;ll hit burnout. You know that exhausting feeling after a good, long run? Think that, but all the time. You are constantly tired, easily distracted with seemingly simpler tasks unable to consider starting something. It&amp;#39;s a monster I had to face yet again in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is Imposter Syndrome?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imposter Syndrome is a psychological phenomena where you are unable to internalize your accomplishments. Even though there is plenty of evidence to show your accomplishments, you still are convinced that its &amp;#39;luck&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;good timing&amp;#39; that got you there. A really great talk by &lt;a href=&quot;http://juliepagano.com/speaking/&quot;&gt;Julie Pagano&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s Dangerous to Go Alone: Battling the Invisible Monsters in Tech&amp;quot; is worth watching as she delivers amazingly helpful information in that talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been here before&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put this into context, I have been programming for roughly 18 years now. I got curious at a young age and never really lost the addiction of solving problems, especially with code. Family members would send me puzzles as gifts and I would solve them almost as fast as I could open the box. However, I almost gave all of that up around 8 years ago and I &lt;a href=&quot;/2013/05/03/don-t-be-nervous.html&quot;&gt;wrote about it&lt;/a&gt; last year. Faced with two really badly executed contracts, it put into question my inexperience with client work, but not my technical skills as a developer and that almost caused me to quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So what happened this time?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After unpacking this recently, I can remember roughly 8 months ago a pivotal moment in my career at my previous job. It was a rather casual conversation regarding my progress and performance. For the last 16 months I had been the sole person building out an ever expanding server infrastructure while automating it with &lt;a href=&quot;http://getchef.com&quot;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;. By then I had also spoken at 4 conferences and had been heavily involved in several major side projects. For those familiar with Imposter Syndrome, you might see where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this casual conversation about my progress and performance, it came up about my performance in context of the development team. While I was applauded for my overall accomplishments, I was told the team had lost confidence in my deliverability and ability to achieve newer goals in system administration. That one conversation shattered my self confidence as if it were a glass statue just hit by a sledgehammer. My initial reaction was confusion and anger. How could I not have gotten that feedback sooner? Why am I not getting help? This quickly devolved into saying things like &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m not good enough, I can&amp;#39;t do anything&amp;quot;. Not very long after that conversation, it became denial. I&amp;#39;d buried the problem and thought &amp;quot;I can prove it to them, I&amp;#39;ll work even harder!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The invisible mountain on your shoulders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you check my twitter feed or even this blog, I&amp;#39;ve done some really crazy and cool things in my life. However, I am generally modest and humble about all of them and am usually the first to doubt my abilities. None of that was enough to feel like I accomplished anything in life so I stacked on more responsibilities. I had taken on several large side projects, maintained a few open source software projects, and started attending more events than I could possibly schedule. Before I knew it, the task list more than filled up weekends and weeknights. I was running and soon forgot why I started to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hitting the brick wall&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ringing in the New Year is a good time to reflect and give some serious thought about the past year. For me however, it slowly became a scary realization that I was burned out from technology. I was dreading going back to work, my side projects languished, and I started stressing out about all the little things. By this time I wasn&amp;#39;t even sure I could continue doing server administration or programming at all. I wasn&amp;#39;t good enough to do it, despite handling 25 servers and a data center move while over 1.5 &lt;em&gt;million&lt;/em&gt; requests slammed the servers each week. You would think I&amp;#39;ve reasonably proven that I can grow and scale servers right? I didn&amp;#39;t think so and that is where Imposter Syndrome gets the better of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the same time I swore off tech conferences entirely for the year, almost never wanting to return. Depression about my career prospects was beginning to sink in heavily and once again I was back in a similar place roughly 8 years ago. I was exhausted, tired, and in tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Turning Point&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stress was really beginning to break me and it was starting to spill over into my relationship with my husband. At one point there was an intervention. He saw how much everything was draining me emotionally and wanted to help stop the pain. Close friends were getting worried and I decided it was time to evaluate my career options. It wasn&amp;#39;t just myself putting me in this situation, my job was also providing additional stress and I needed to leave. Slowly, I began asking around for opportunities and trying to find other places to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up doing several job interviews and weighing my options. Even going so far as seeking career advice from some close friends with my situation. Do I choose to stay and hope for the better or maybe go with a new job and try to hope for the best? Quit all together? It was hard to decide while still working day to day in technology. My personal investment was seemingly outweighing my own mental health and that was becoming dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had already scheduled time off to attend a Furry Convention. One place I could be silly, see friends, and generally have a good time away from technology. I remember packing up my laptop just in case and stashing it in the hotel safe. The only time I took it back out was when it was time to head home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed that weekend off to decompress, de-stress, and reflect. I woke up the next morning and sat down with a cup of coffee to write my resignation letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Picking up the pieces&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m fortunate to have amazing support from my husband and some close friends through this part of my life this time around. I was able to seek some career advice and get some perspective on the last 8 years of my career. It was a really slow process that involved a lot of emotions and that recurring self doubt. I remember gaining a lot of confidence when I began interviewing at other companies and having to go over my accomplishments. That was when things really began to sink in and build me back up as a person. Not only was someone else impressed with what I had done, but I was too. For the first time, I thought there was a good chance I could continue enjoying what I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;It&amp;#39;s not over yet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish there was a way to fast forward my progress, but its been a slow and steady recovery since the New Year. I&amp;#39;m now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://dnsimple.com/&quot;&gt;DNSimple&lt;/a&gt; and beginning to get my footing there. What has been the hardest part of working there is actually taking feedback and internalizing it. The team has put lots of trust in me to do my job and my opinions matter because of my experience. Honestly, it&amp;#39;s still hard to enthusiastically say I work at a great company and love what I do, but I feel I&amp;#39;m building that love and enthusiasm day by day. Meanwhile, I am slowly reconnecting to my past commitments and starting over again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>Sometimes the assumption from others is that my job is easy. I sit in front of a computer all day and type on a keyboard. How stressful is that? Very. I always equate it to running a marathon in your head. You are constantly practicing, making quick decisions, acting on instinct, always driving, and generally being amplified by Caffeine. When you begin piling on all those responsibilities and doing too much for too long, your brain will give up and you&amp;#39;ll hit burnout. You know that exhausting feeling after a good, long run? Think that, but all the time. You are constantly tired, easily distracted with seemingly simpler tasks unable to consider starting something. It&amp;#39;s a monster I had to face yet again in my career.</summary></entry><entry><title>Some well-kept Chicago Developer Secrets</title><link href="/2014/02/21/some-well-kept-chicago-developer-secrets.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some well-kept Chicago Developer Secrets" /><published>2014-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2014-02-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2014/02/21/some-well-kept-chicago-developer-secrets</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2014/02/21/some-well-kept-chicago-developer-secrets.html">&lt;p&gt;More than once (especially by software development students) I have been asked for tips on networking and learning about software. It&amp;#39;s not a big set of tips, but useful information to know for people looking to break into this career or need to expand their horizons. Remember this is my advice and personal opinions. If you disagree or think I&amp;#39;m missing somwthing, please contact me via the various mediums at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;#1 - Walk through the open office doors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chicago is home to &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of development studios and believe it or not, many of them have an &amp;#39;open door&amp;#39; policy. This policy is part marketing and part recruiting as it helps give back by hosting developers in their office. It also fosters a low-pressure environment to meet and evaluate potential employment candidates. In some ways, it&amp;#39;s a great way for their developers to possibly learn new things from random visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re looking for a job, seeking mentorship, or simply want to meet and hang out with developers. Reach out to the many shops and simply ask if you can spend a day or part of a day with them. You would be shocked at how many will not only say yes, but welcome you with open arms and sometimes even offer you a free lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2014/02/14/my-remote-life-lessons-and-tips.html&quot;&gt;Working remotely&lt;/a&gt; does provide the advantage of being able to visit other offices and network. It&amp;#39;s my #1 tip to all new developers wanting to know how and where to connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;#2 - Mentorship is a two-way street&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is one of the things I seek out personally and attempt to provide as a means to give back to the software development community. Simply dispensing advice, guidence, or career advice; can mean worlds to someone new or continuing their journey of software development. One thing I&amp;#39;ve heard from other mentors helping students is that people notoriously don&amp;#39;t seek out experienced people for help or advice. Even with formalized systems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://mentoring.devbootcamp.com&quot;&gt;pairing is caring&lt;/a&gt; there is very little uptake in help when offered. This isn&amp;#39;t because mentors are being lazy, but because they are busy and students seemingly feel afraid to approach them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re seeking mentorship, know that the mentor&amp;#39;s time is valuable, especially their free time. You will likely have to chase them down for help, not the other way around. Offer to take them to lunch, have a cup of coffee, or a beer to socialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;#3 - Attend meetups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chicago on any given week; there is a meetup practically every day (including weekends) for a programming language, framework, or methodology. If your Friday afternoons are available, consider attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://university.8thlight.com/&quot;&gt;8th Light University&lt;/a&gt; or if Tuesday afternoon works better checkout &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Geekfest/&quot;&gt;Geekfest&lt;/a&gt;. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/find/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; and search for your favorite programming language or framework. Chances are a meetup is happening soon and you could attend to find some new friends. Sometimes these meetups are sponsored with free food and drinks too, which is a bonus for the starving (or broke) student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get out there!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this advice boils down to getting you to put yourself out there for everyone. Follow the sage advice from my favorite networking book of all time &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People&quot;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt; to help create and foster friendships for years to come. Your life &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; career will thank you for it later!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>More than once (especially by software development students) I have been asked for tips on networking and learning about software. It&amp;#39;s not a big set of tips, but useful information to know for people looking to break into this career or need to expand their horizons. Remember this is my advice and personal opinions. If you disagree or think I&amp;#39;m missing somwthing, please contact me via the various mediums at the bottom of the page.</summary></entry><entry><title>My Remote Life: Lessons and Tips</title><link href="/2014/02/14/my-remote-life-lessons-and-tips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Remote Life: Lessons and Tips" /><published>2014-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2014-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2014/02/14/my-remote-life--lessons-and-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2014/02/14/my-remote-life-lessons-and-tips.html">&lt;p&gt;For nearly two years I have been working remotely for &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;#39;d like to share some lessons learned along with a few tips of how I adjusted. Be warned that some of these tips are a little biased around some of the benefits and current structure of Treehouse. Also know that these are my personal views and not that of Treehouse in particular. Shifting to a remote-based working style has been a little bit of a struggle, but I&amp;#39;ve learned to embrace and enjoy its affordance of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before joining Treehouse, I used to work in the Chicago office for &lt;a href=&quot;http://hashrocket.com&quot;&gt;Hashrocket&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;d spend up to 2 hours daily commuting via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transitchicago.com/&quot;&gt;CTA&lt;/a&gt;, taking two trains to and from work every day. While I enjoyed working there and learned quite a great deal; joining Treehouse was a jarring experience when shifting to remote based work. I wasn&amp;#39;t seeing my co-workers or visiting an office every day and initially I missed it a lot. Routines, like personal habits, can be difficult to break, but not all of them had to be broken for me. That is where my first tip comes in to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Dress like you&amp;#39;re going to the office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#39;t recall where this tip came from, but I had read somewhere that the psychological effect of putting on your typical work uniform helps give you a mental breaking point. It helps simulate that &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m going to work&amp;quot; routine to get you into the working mindset. Some have suggested going to a nearby coffee shop to simulate walking to work. This helped me tremendously, especially if you end up doing video calls with co-workers as I would have felt embarrassed to show up in a bathrobe and messed up hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Take regular breaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already had this habit from my previous job and can&amp;#39;t stress this enough for working at home. Working in my home office I&amp;#39;m so comfortable that I sometimes go hours without getting up to go eat or grab a drink of water. There are a few techniques I&amp;#39;ve tried to force myself into breaks, but none have seemed to stick. My rule of thumb has always been that if I begin feeling frustrated or stuck, I get up and walk or grab some fresh air. Walking in general also helps with your cognitive ability, as I learned from &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainrules.net/&quot;&gt;Brain Rules&lt;/a&gt;. Speaking of getting out of the office:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Get out of the home office at least once a week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly 3 weeks into working for Treehouse I began to feel a little depressed about working remotely. I missed the commute and having a physical office with co-workers to chat with and debate ideas. I felt very disconnected despite being in a chatroom with co-workers every day. I decided that I needed to try co-working to see if it would help relieve that depression. I&amp;#39;m pretty fortunate to live and work in Chicago where many local offices have open-door policies for co-working. Since implementing this rule and following it, I&amp;#39;ve gained many new and better friendships along with noticably more happiness at work. It has been the single best thing to improve my overall remote working experience. Places I never would have visited such as restaurants and coffee shops are easier to plan for and investigate when you can control the schedule working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Grab a good pair of headphones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have been able to better control my distractions by working remotely. Visiting offices can be both rewarding and detrimental to me. Working in a noisy coffee shop is easier when you have a pair of headphones to drown the grinders and steam hissing. Many offices have adopted the &amp;quot;do not disturb&amp;quot; rule when someone has headphones going. You can get yourself into &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/how-github-works-asynchronous&quot;&gt;The Zone&lt;/a&gt; a whole lot easier. I personally have a pair of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.logitech.com/en-us/support/ue500?crid=1419&quot;&gt;UE 500&amp;#39;s from Logitech&lt;/a&gt; and carry them everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Control distractions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offices tend to be a double edged sword for me. On one hand they are a wonderful way to socialize and fill that void of loneliness of working from home. On the other, for those very same reasons, it can be easy to get into debates or chatting rather than paying attention to the task at hand. When working from home or at an office, keep your communication options to a minimum set to avoid side-tracking on things. Every time I violate this rule I wonder why I feel unproductive that day and this is generally why. I&amp;#39;ll give attention to task B, C, D instead of A and while thats still productivity, it doesn&amp;#39;t always help the primary task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything will feel like it needs attention &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; and usually that is not always the case. Feel empowered to disconnect communication services like email, IM, IRC, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tip: Communicate more effectively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the biggest changes I felt when switching to remote because I still struggle with it to this day. When you begin working remotely you realize how much unwritten communication happens in an office. Body language, verbal cues, explanations in general, are much harder to articulate with text if you&amp;#39;re unexperienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m still working on this part personally, even after almost 2 years at Treehouse and feel I&amp;#39;m slowly getting better at this with feedback. There is no doubt I am working hard, but not everyone understands my descriptions or knows what is going on in my world. Picking back up on my blog is one of many things I have employed to get better at this skill since its crucial to remote work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>For nearly two years I have been working remotely for Treehouse and I&amp;#39;d like to share some lessons learned along with a few tips of how I adjusted. Be warned that some of these tips are a little biased around some of the benefits and current structure of Treehouse. Also know that these are my personal views and not that of Treehouse in particular. Shifting to a remote-based working style has been a little bit of a struggle, but I&amp;#39;ve learned to embrace and enjoy its affordance of freedom.</summary></entry><entry><title>Don&amp;#39;t Be Nervous</title><link href="/2013/05/03/don-t-be-nervous.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don&#39;t Be Nervous" /><published>2013-05-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-05-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2013/05/03/don-t-be-nervous</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2013/05/03/don-t-be-nervous.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there. My name is Aaron Kalin and I&amp;#39;m here to tell you &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t be nervous.&amp;quot; Actually, I&amp;#39;m really here to talk about how to break out of your shell. People in technology, especially developers, tend to be introverted. Nothing wrong with that, but it can&amp;#39;t hurt to be a little social and put yourself out there. I&amp;#39;m going to share my short story in the hopes it might inspire others out there in a similar situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rough beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s jump back to 2006. At the time, I was a fed up PHP developer working freelance. Ready to quit programming from lousy contracts and employers taking advantage of me. A friend messaged me the year prior about this new web framework called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubyonrails.org/&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;. It quickly gained popularity from the 10 minute blog video. A conference was recently announced to be held in Chicago. I assumed RailsConf would be my ticket to a new career in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Meeting people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived early to the first day of the conference during workshops. Since I barely had enough for the conference ticket, I went next door to the open space and sat down at a large round table. Soon, others started to stream in and next to me sat Chad Fowler. Being too nervous to introduce myself, I kept quiet and kept coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in the day, someone piped up and asked around the table about what we were working on in Rails. Eventually I chimed in with &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m porting a PHP app over to Rails, but I&amp;#39;m wanting to use this attachment fu plugin and there isn&amp;#39;t much documentation, need to ask this technoweenie guy about how it works.&amp;quot; That is when Chad Fowler leaned over and said &amp;quot;You should ask him, he&amp;#39;s sitting right there&amp;quot; as he pointed out Rick Olson, also known as technoweenie sitting across the table. That was an utterly embarrassing moment for me and it gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Missed opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day the conference was in full swing. I sat down to lunch with two gentlemen. After introducing myself this time, I learned one was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mornini.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Tom Mornini&lt;/a&gt; and the other was a speaker, &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainspl.at/&quot;&gt;Ezra Zygmuntowicz&lt;/a&gt;. Both were about to create a startup around rails deployment called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engineyard.com/&quot;&gt;Engine Yard&lt;/a&gt;. After some discussions over lunch about my work history, Tom handed me a business card and asked me to contact him about employment at his new startup. I wasn&amp;#39;t confident enough to respond, thinking I lacked the skills needed to work with them. Don&amp;#39;t worry, this story gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Try not to be a fanboy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the final day of the conference, I was headed down the hallway before the concert with Why the Lucky Stiff and the Thirsty Cups. I spotted &lt;a href=&quot;http://david.heinemeierhansson.com/&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; heading to the lounge area. Thinking this would be a cool chance to meet the creator of Rails, I seized my opportunity and introduced myself. What proceeded afterwards was something along the lines of &amp;quot;Hey David, im such and such on IRC, I submitted a documentation patch and thanks for making Rails&amp;quot; or at least that is how I think it was said. I was so nervous and so amped up that the entire sentence came out in one long statement with no punctuation. As David nervously shook my hand. I&amp;#39;m sure his impression of me was probably &amp;quot;What a creep!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Depression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the conference, I was able to network enough to get two freelance contracts. One was a project to port a PHP application to Rails and another was to move an old ASP site to Rails. What I did not know was that both projects were already spiraling out of control when I arrived. Not able to do much, they quickly turned into the two worst contracts I have ever executed in my career. Quickly leaving both of them, I fell into depression, thinking I could not hack it in Rails. My lack of interpersonal skills has finally bitten me hard and I paid the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was I to do? I still loved programming and had been doing it for over a decade at that point. I was hurt badly, but still in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of running away from programming, I decided to face my social anxieties directly. I wanted to join a retail store to be put in front of customers and learn how to interact. This would provide valuable skills in customer service, negotiation, and empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;#39;t long before I was hanging out at the local EBGames (now Gamestop) and was soon offered a job there. The manager initially did not want to hire me because of my obvious lack of customer service skills, but felt I could learn with training. Eventually I got the hang of things and soon ran into people who worked at the local Apple store. After applying several times, I eventually got an offer to work there about 2 years after starting with EBGames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working at Apple was very different given the massive amount of traffic to their stores. I joined just past the initial iPhone launch and business was picking up steadily. I eventually joined the Genius team and was soon in a customer service position. Nothing teaches you empathy faster than consoling a parent who lost their child&amp;#39;s first few years of digital photos because they forgot to back them up somewhere. That job taught me a lot about working with a team, empathizing with customers, and explaining very technical subject matters to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I realized it was time to get back to programming. Roughly three years later, I started applying to different Rails developer positions. Given how long I had been away from programming, my chances were fairly slim to finding something. This is where I started focusing on companies offering internships or apprenticeship programs. A prominent apprenticeship I read about was with &lt;a href=&quot;http://hashrocket.com/&quot;&gt;Hashrocket&lt;/a&gt; and I applied to their Chicago office. There was one problem with that application. They did not have an apprenticeship program in Chicago. After some persistence on my part, I was eventually hired on as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those painful experiences taught me a few key things about how to break out of my shell. I hope they can help you too with advancing your career and helping your life overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to network with others. Not just on-line, but off-line as well via meetings or local user groups. Shake hands, repeat names and make connections. You never know who you&amp;#39;ll meet as it could lead to awesome things for you in the future. Meeting the organizers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagoruby.org/&quot;&gt;Chicago Ruby&lt;/a&gt; lead to my first presentation and my success thereon lead to speaking elsewhere. You don&amp;#39;t have to be a social butterfly to be effective at networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Present&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons why I present at conferences and user groups now. Chief among them is to force myself to meet others. It&amp;#39;s possibly not for everyone, but something to have as a goal when you work on your inter-networking skills. Lots of people will help you prepare for a presentation, just have to ask. User groups are usually a great start, but go smaller and present in front of some of those people you networked with already so the pressure is not as high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Awkward is good&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have gone to large conferences and small user groups, but you can tell I&amp;#39;m shy. Working myself up to saying &amp;#39;hello&amp;#39; instead of a head nod is difficult. Despite having done presentations in front of 300 people. Change won&amp;#39;t happen overnight, but you have to be aware you have those hangups and work past them. People around you are probably just as nervous as you and breaking the ice has a very positive effect. Stay positive and keep pushing yourself. It&amp;#39;s fine to extrovert yourself once in a while then you can go right back to being introverted. You&amp;#39;re just as beautiful either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this post has helped inspire you as much as it has others when I give this as a lightning talk at conferences. My story isn&amp;#39;t very unique and I know developers who struggle with depression or social anxiety. I&amp;#39;m fortunate to have figured out a way past my quirks without medication, but recommend you seek a therapist if you still find it difficult. A lot of why I stay around the Ruby community is the large group of really helpful and smart people. Stay positive folks and remember. Don&amp;#39;t be nervous.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>Hi there. My name is Aaron Kalin and I&amp;#39;m here to tell you &amp;quot;Don&amp;#39;t be nervous.&amp;quot; Actually, I&amp;#39;m really here to talk about how to break out of your shell. People in technology, especially developers, tend to be introverted. Nothing wrong with that, but it can&amp;#39;t hurt to be a little social and put yourself out there. I&amp;#39;m going to share my short story in the hopes it might inspire others out there in a similar situation.</summary></entry><entry><title>You have only yourself</title><link href="/2013/03/08/you-have-only-yourself.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You have only yourself" /><published>2013-03-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2013-03-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2013/03/08/you-have-only-yourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2013/03/08/you-have-only-yourself.html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not one to write poetry, but I woke up one morning a few months back
inspired to write. At the time there was a fair amount of drama going on
twitter (when is it not?) and that likely inspired my writing. This was well
received as a lightning talk at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/scna&quot;&gt;SCNA&lt;/a&gt; last year and I wanted to share this
with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is terrible, who the hell wrote this?&amp;quot; I hear in an office.
That statement is shortly followed by fingers at a keyboard typing a command.
A brief pause as they read the output and let out a sigh.
&amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s me&amp;quot; I hear in a shameful tone that perfectly describes his or her current state.
They used that command that I love to hate.
&amp;#39;git blame&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll admit it. I&amp;#39;ve been there too.
Usually you&amp;#39;re knee deep in a code base where you have a doubt.
You happen upon something so vile, so horrifying that you freak out!
In a knee-jerk reaction you might shout &amp;quot;What the fuck?&amp;quot;
And before you know it, type that command.
Then suddenly, a reason isn&amp;#39;t so in demand.
It&amp;#39;s you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was that code so horrible? Can that commit message tell you?
50 characters or less isn&amp;#39;t very much to discuss your life story.
Or explain why that chunk of code had to be so gory.
You see, at the time I had this deadline to meet and a client promise to keep.
That code worked! I swear it passed the test.
Maybe, I didn&amp;#39;t get my full nights rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I emplore everyone here to take a step back.
When that chunk of code makes your brain go off-track.
Stop typing that command in vain.
Because then you have only yourself to &amp;#39;git blame&amp;#39;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>I&amp;#39;m not one to write poetry, but I woke up one morning a few months back
inspired to write. At the time there was a fair amount of drama going on
twitter (when is it not?) and that likely inspired my writing. This was well
received as a lightning talk at SCNA last year and I wanted to share this
with everyone.</summary></entry><entry><title>Better Presentations</title><link href="/2012/08/06/better-presentations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better Presentations" /><published>2012-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2012/08/06/better-presentations</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2012/08/06/better-presentations.html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had a few people ask me for advice on how I approach creating
presentations. This was broken out from my &amp;quot;Choose your own
adventure&amp;quot; talk that I didn&amp;#39;t get to cover, but I felt this is worth recording
and releasing to help anyone with curiosity about my approach to making
presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the video below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/47000092&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>I&amp;#39;ve had a few people ask me for advice on how I approach creating
presentations. This was broken out from my &amp;quot;Choose your own
adventure&amp;quot; talk that I didn&amp;#39;t get to cover, but I felt this is worth recording
and releasing to help anyone with curiosity about my approach to making
presentations.</summary></entry><entry><title>Rails 3 and Cucumber</title><link href="/2010/09/20/rails3-and-cucumber.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rails 3 and Cucumber" /><published>2010-09-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-09-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2010/09/20/rails3-and-cucumber</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2010/09/20/rails3-and-cucumber.html">&lt;p&gt;Diving into Rails 3 has been fun and frustrating these past couple of months. There have been ups and downs, frustrations and entirely new experiences learning this framework all over again. Overall, I am incredibly impressed with the changes made to the framework.  I look back at my super-old Rails 1.0 projects when the framework first hit to now and I honestly can&amp;#39;t recognize what I wrote back then. Back then Rails was an unpolished, rough framework with a noble idea of crushing the notions of XML configurations and repeating yourself.  Today it is still the opinionated framework I fell in love with, but with some flexibility in the right places.  You can still stick to their standard, but very easily apply your own thanks to cleverly implemented agnosticism of components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this fresh look at the new Rails, I decided to take the plunge with &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspec.info/&quot;&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cukes.info/&quot;&gt;Cucumber&lt;/a&gt; for testing versus Test::Unit. The first thing that took me was the syntax and how easy it really was to make tests. Cucumber feels like writing an epic novel of user interaction, discovery and sometimes failed experimentation.  My only initial hurdle was the slowness of loading the test environment upon running each test, but thanks to add-ons like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sporkrb/spork&quot;&gt;Spork&lt;/a&gt; I was able to speed things up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll need more time to become a serious expert, but I was shocked to see how quickly I could pick this system up. Things are organized, flexible and extensible.  Much like a framework I am used to using, except its there to help me be a better developer to myself and my clients. Of course I will have to remember to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LfmAzLAKKoc&quot;&gt;Test All The Fucking Time&lt;/a&gt; when programming now. If you have a doubt, write more test coverage. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>Diving into Rails 3 has been fun and frustrating these past couple of months. There have been ups and downs, frustrations and entirely new experiences learning this framework all over again. Overall, I am incredibly impressed with the changes made to the framework.  I look back at my super-old Rails 1.0 projects when the framework first hit to now and I honestly can&amp;#39;t recognize what I wrote back then. Back then Rails was an unpolished, rough framework with a noble idea of crushing the notions of XML configurations and repeating yourself.  Today it is still the opinionated framework I fell in love with, but with some flexibility in the right places.  You can still stick to their standard, but very easily apply your own thanks to cleverly implemented agnosticism of components.</summary></entry><entry><title>Adventures in automation</title><link href="/2010/04/12/adventures-in-automation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adventures in automation" /><published>2010-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2010-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2010/04/12/adventures-in-automation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2010/04/12/adventures-in-automation.html">&lt;p&gt;Been a little while since my last post here.  A short explanation of the last 4 months in bullet point format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved to Tampa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turned 25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overtime at work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Studying for the CCNA and A+ exams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time was a precious commodity the past few months and I finally got a chance to breathe, collect myself and write a new post.  While trying to write this post, I managed to update some of the code running this blog to help automate posting and updating of my resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one feature that I spent far too much time researching was converting my resume to pdf automatically when I publish a change.  I honestly don&amp;#39;t update it that much, but I thought it would be an easy task to generate it once I updated it with some new information.  So my search began for a markdown to pdf tool. Ultimately I went with wkhtmltopdf, but I&amp;#39;ll give some reasoning why I did not choose the other projects I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.htmldoc.org/&quot;&gt;HTMLDoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately did not respect any CSS, so my pdf was this lifeless, unformatted page that looked like something out of the mid 90s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.princexml.com/&quot;&gt;Prince&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very nice tool, the free one watermarks your pdf files and the &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot; license is nearly $500.  Would be nice to use for a commercial CMS where dynamic PDF download is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xhtmlrenderer.dev.java.net/&quot;&gt;Flying Saucer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written in Java, so it was a bit complicated to setup, but could be called via JRuby.  Did not feel like respecting the print stylesheet either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/wkhtmltopdf/&quot;&gt;wkhtmltopdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone came up with the brilliant idea of making a command line wrapper around Qt&amp;#39;s implementation of WebKit (the Safari browsing engine) purely for making PDFs out of HTML pages.  It worked flawlessly, except on my Snow Leopard mac when I feed it the option to load the print style.  I was forced to run this on an Ubuntu system I manage at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may make a second part to this post about the automation I&amp;#39;ve done on this blog, but for now you can take a peek at the commented code in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/martinisoft/martinisoft.github.io/blob/source/Rakefile&quot;&gt;Rakefile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>Been a little while since my last post here.  A short explanation of the last 4 months in bullet point format:</summary></entry><entry><title>Dusting off the cobwebs</title><link href="/2009/11/22/dusting-off-the-cobwebs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dusting off the cobwebs" /><published>2009-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2009-11-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2009/11/22/dusting-off-the-cobwebs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2009/11/22/dusting-off-the-cobwebs.html">&lt;p&gt;Took many months, but I finally found some time to clean up and update my site design.  I owe a lot of the inspiration and code to Dan Cederholm&amp;#39;s new book &lt;a href=&quot;http://handcraftedcss.com/&quot;&gt;Handcrafted CSS&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My strong suit is not web design and I have always struggled with keeping up on the latest innovations in that area.  Lately, I have made a conscious effort to follow leading designers and their published material.  The books that stuck and got me thinking differently were the books authored by &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplebits.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Cederholm&lt;/a&gt;.  His style and explanations are simple to follow while comparing methods to a solution.  This works wonderfully for a logical guy like myself where I want to know what method works for certain situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is the updated design you see here.  I&amp;#39;ve littered my site with credits to &lt;a href=&quot;http://simplebits.com/&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://meyerweb.com/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer&lt;/a&gt; to give props to these design gurus.  If you&amp;#39;re wondering where I got the palette and design ideas, it was inspired by Dan Webb&amp;#39;s new outfit &lt;a href=&quot;http://massiverobot.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Massive Robot&lt;/a&gt;.  You could call me an imitator, but I&amp;#39;m happy to give credit where it is due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still more work to do, but this was a major milestone for me and giving me things to think about for next year.  I am moving to Tampa next month so the next entry may come after the new year when I am settled into my new apartment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;martinisoft&quot;}</name></author><summary>Took many months, but I finally found some time to clean up and update my site design.  I owe a lot of the inspiration and code to Dan Cederholm&amp;#39;s new book Handcrafted CSS.</summary></entry></feed>
